Guide to the Sinclair Lewis Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Sinclair Lewis papers
1866-1964
1910-1950
YCAL MSS 268
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
48.92
95 boxes + 7 broadside folders
The Sinclair Lewis Papers consist of manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, and personal papers documenting the life and work of novelist and author Sinclair Lewis.
Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951
Dehn, Adolf, 1895-1968
Fleischmann, Trude, 1895-1990
Friedman, Philip Allan
Hassam, Childe, 1859-1935
Maule, Harry E. (Harry Edward), 1886-
Schaal, Eric
Thurber, James, 1894-1961
Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964
Morgan Guaranty Trust Company of New York
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Sinclair Lewis Papers were acquired through various gifts and purchases. The papers consist chiefly of gifts from Sinclair Lewis and the Lewis estate, including legal executors Ernst, Cane, Berner & Gitlin, dating from 1937 to 1967, with the bulk of the gifts dating from 1938 to 1952. Additional gifts and purchases of material by or relating to Sinclair Lewis from other sources were added to the papers between 1940 and 1985. These materials have been kept with the papers for research purposes and the provenance of larger gifts from Harry E. Maule, Philip Friedman, and the Morgan Guaranty Trust Company has been preserved.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 89-91: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Separated Materials
Records for printed materials cataloged separately may be found in Orbis. See the following call numbers: Za L588 +1, Za L588 +2, Za L588 +3, Za L588 +4, Za L588 +5, Za L588 +S1, Za L588 +S2, Za L588 +T1, and Za L588 +T2.
Works by Childe Hassam were transferred to the Yale University Art Gallery on permanent loan.
Existence and Location of Copies
Microfilm available through Access Services.
Sinclair Lewis (1885-1951)
Sinclair Lewis was a major cultural figure in the United States in the first half of the 20th century and, though he is best known as a novelist and social critic, he also wrote plays, poetry, and short fiction. Lewis was awarded the Pulitzer Prize in 1926 and, in 1930, he was the first American author to win the Nobel Prize for Literature. In addition to critical and bibliographic scholarship on Lewis, summary information is available in the standard print and online biographical resources.
Scope and Contents
The Sinclair Lewis Papers, which consist of manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, and personal papers, document Lewis's literary output, creative process, and the role he played in the public and intellectual life of the United States in the first half of the twentieth century. Writings in the collection feature materials for twenty-four of Lewis's novels dating from 1909 to 1951, with the bulk dating from plans for Babbit (1921) to page proofs for The Godseeker (1949). Materials include background material and notes, character sketches and plans, drafts, galley and page proofs, scripts and screenplays for theatrical and cinematic adaptations, and printed publicity and reviews. In addition to the materials for novels, there are notes, drafts, scripts, and other materials relating to seven plays and a rich variety of shorter works, including book reviews, essays, poems, short stories, and speeches.
The correspondence in the Lewis papers features single letters or small groups of letters to and from American and English writers and literary scholars and critics of the late nineteenth to mid twentieth century. Noteworthy correspondents include Sherwood Anderson, Stephen Vincent Benét, Bernard Berenson, Willa Cather, F. Scott Fitzgerald, Ernest Hemingway, William Dean Howells, Jack London, Compton Mackenzie, Thomas Mann, W. Somerset Maugham, H. L. Mencken, Upton Sinclair, Chauncey Brewster Tinker, Rebecca West, Edith Wharton, and Thornton Wilder, among others. There is also correspondence with family, friends, publishers, and organizations.
Photographs include snapshots, studio and artists' portraits, and stage scenes from plays and theatrical adaptations of novels. Photographs date from family scenes in early childhood (1894) to a portrait in Florence, Italy (1950). Studio and artists' portraits of Lewis include photographs by Robert H. Davis, Trude Fleischmann, Eric Schaal, and Carl Van Vechten. There are also photographs of Grace MacKowan Cooke, Irving Fisher, Albert Payson Terhune, Dorothy Thompson, and members of the Lewis and Kermott families.
Personal Papers feature artwork, diaries, and notes and notebooks. The artwork in the collection includes original drawings, etchings and lithographs of Lewis by Richard Hood, James Thurber, and others. The diaries, written in English and in code, date chiefly from 1900 to 1907, and include notes relating to life in high school in Sauk Centre, Minnesota and at Oberlin College and Yale University. Copies of the early diaries include transcriptions of the English-language portions of the text and translations of the coded portions of the text. The twenty-nine folders of notes and notebooks, dating from 1907 to 1950, include research for unidentified writing projects and loose manuscript material.
The Lewis papers also contain materials by and relating to Lewis from Harry E. Maule, Philip Friedman, and the Morgan Guaranty Trust Company. The Maule materials include correspondence, manuscripts, and other papers relating chiefly to the publication of Lewis's novels in the 1940s. The Friedman and Morgan Guaranty Trust Company materials consist of correspondence and financial and legal records respectively.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into seven series: I. Writings, 1905-1963. II. Correspondence, 1866-1964. III. Photographs, 1888-1950. IV. Personal Papers, 1886-1950. V. Harry E. Maule Material, 1917-1963. VI. Philip Friedman Material, 1923-1953. VII. Morgan Guaranty Trust Company Material, 1917-1946.
American drama -- 20th Century; American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Florence (Italy); Sauk Centre (Minn.); United States -- Intellectual life -- 20th Century; United States -- Social life and customs -- 20th Century; Lithographs; Oil paintings (visual works); Photographic prints; Authors; Studio portraits; Anderson, Sherwood, 1876-1941; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943; Berenson, Bernard, 1865-1959; Cather, Willa, 1873-1947; Cooke, Grace MacGowan, 1863-1944; Fisher, Irving, 1867-1947; Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1896-1940; Friedman, Philip Allan; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961; Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982; Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951; London, Jack, 1876-1916; Mackenzie, Compton, 1883-1972; Mann, Thomas, 1875-1955; Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), 1874-1965; Maule, Harry E. (Harry Edward), 1886-; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968; Terhune, Albert Payson, 1872-1942; Thompson, Dorothy, 1893-1961; Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963; West, Rebecca, 1892-1983; Wharton, Edith, 1862-1937; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Kermott family; Lewis family; Morgan Guaranty Trust Company of New York; Oberlin College; Yale University
- Writings, 1905-1963; Series I; 18.35 linear feet (45 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I, Writings, housed in boxes 1-45, is organized into two subseries: Writings of Sinclair Lewis and Writings of Others. Writings of Sinclair Lewis is subdivided for Novels, Plays, and Shorter Works, and titles within each subdivision are arranged alphabetically. Writings of Others is arranged alphabetically by author.
  Scope and Contents
  The Writings of Sinclair Lewis subseries features material for twenty-four of Lewis's novels, including background material and notes, character sketches and plans, drafts, galley and page proofs, playscripts and screenplays for theatrical and cinematic adaptations, and printed publicity and reviews. Novels date from 1909 to 1951, with the bulk dating from plans for Babbit (1921) to page proofs for The Godseeker (1949).
  In addition to the novels, there are notes, drafts, scripts, and other materials relating to seven plays and a rich variety of shorter works, including book reviews, essays, poems, short stories, and speeches. The poems, for example, date as early as 1905 and as late as 1950.
  The Writings of Others subseries consists of biographies, literary analysis, and memorial tributes relating to Lewis.
  - WRITINGS OF SINCLAIR LEWIS
    - Novels
      - Ann Vickers
        - Draft, incomplete, chapter 22 to end, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
        - Publicity, undated
      - Arrowsmith
        - Draft, 1924 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
        - Galley proof, 1925
        - Page proof, 1925
      - Babbit
        - Plan, 1921 January (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Drafts, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 8-11)
      - Bethel Merriday
        - Notes and plan, [circa 1938] (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
        - Drafts, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 14-20)
        - Draft, 1939 October 27 (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
        - Galley proof, 1939 December 13
      - Cass Timberlane
        - Notes and sketches, undated (Box 4, Folder 23-26)
        - Plans, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 27-29)
        - Drafts, miscellaneous pages, 1944 July 1 (Box 4, Folder 30)
        - Drafts, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 31-37)
        - Draft, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 38-39)
        - Galley proof, 1945 March
        - Page proofs, 1945 April
        - Film script, 1947 March 20 (Box 6, Folder 40)
          Includes letter to Lewis, dated April 8, 1947, from Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer
      - The Children's Children
        - Notes, 1909 November (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - Dodsworth
        - Notes and sketches, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
        - Drafts, 1927, undated (Box 6, Folder 43-45)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 7, Folder 46-51)
        - Galley proof, [1928?] December 17
        - Page proof, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 52)
        - Playscripts, 1932-1933 (Box 8, Folder 53-54)
        - Galley proof for adaptation, [1933?]
        - Page proof for adaptation, 1933-1934 (Box 8, Folder 55)
        - Reviews, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - Elmer Gantry
        - Draft, 1926 June 9 (Box 8, Folder 57-61)
        - Draft, undated (Box 9, Folder 62-65)
        - Galley proof, [1926-1927?]
        - Page proof, 1927
      - The Enchantment of Elaine Kent
        - Drafts, undated (Box 9, Folder 66-67)
      - Gideon Planish
        - Notes and sketches, undated (Box 9, Folder 68)
        - Draft, 1941 May 10 (Box 9, Folder 69-71)
        - Drafts, 1942 June 20 (Box 10, Folder 72-77)
        - Draft, undated (Box 11, Folder 78-80)
        - Galley proofs, 1943 January
        - Page proofs, 1943 January
        - Screenplay suggestions, 1943 July 19 (Box 11, Folder 81)
      - The Godseeker
        - Background material, undated (Box 11, Folder 82-90)
        - Background material and notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 91-92)
        - Sketches and plans, undated (Box 12, Folder 93-97)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 12, Folder 98)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 13, Folder 99-105)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 106-109)
        - Page proof, 1949
      - A Handbook of Jealousy
        - Drafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 110-112)
      - It Can't Happen Here
        - Notes and plan, undated (Box 15, Folder 113-114)
        - Drafts, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 115-120)
        - Drafts, 1935-1937, undated (Box 16, Folder 121-127)
        - Playscript, drafts, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 128-134)
        - Playscript, drafts, 1936, undated (Box 18, Folder 135-142)
        - Casting sheet for original production, undated (Box 18, Folder 143)
        - Playscript, second version, drafts, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 144-148)
        - Screenplay, 1936 January 22 (Box 19, Folder 149)
        - WPA Report, undated (Box 19, Folder 150)
        - List of copies distributed, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 151)
      - Kingsblood Royal
        - Notes, undated (Box 20, Folder 152)
        - Plan, undated (Box 20, Folder 153-155)
        - Draft, 1946 April 20 (Box 20, Folder 156-159)
        - Draft, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 160-162)
        - Galley proof, 1946 October
        - Page proof, 1946 November 21
        - Reviews, undated (Box 21, Folder 163)
        - Playscript by H.S. Kraft, undated (Box 21, Folder 164)
      - Let's Play King
        - Drafts, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 165-167)
      - Main Street
        - Proofs of illustrations, undated (Box 21, Folder 168)
      - The Man Who Knew Coolidge
        - Photograph of unidentified man [Calvin Coolidge?], undated (Box 22, Folder 169)
        - "Way I Look at It" (original opening), undated (Box 22, Folder 170)
        - Draft, undated (Box 22, Folder 171)
        - Galley proof, 1928 January
        - Page proofs, 1928 (Box 22, Folder 172)
      - Mantrap
        - Notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 173)
        - Drafts, 1926, undated (Box 22, Folder 174-177)
        - Page proofs, 1926 (Box 22, Folder 178)
      - The Prodigal Parents
        - Notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 179)
        - Draft, 1937 September 15 (Box 23, Folder 180-185)
        - Galley proofs, 1937 October
        - Page proofs, 1937 October
      - Our Mr. Wrenn
        - Galley Proof, undated (Box 24, Folder 186)
      - Over the Body of Lucy Jade
        - Drafts, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 187-191)
        - Revision of chapter 5, 1949 April 16 (Box 24, Folder 192)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 25, Folder 193-196)
      - Work of Art
        - Draft, undated (Box 25, Folder 197)
        - Publicity, undated
      - World So Wide
        - Notes and plan, undated (Box 25, Folder 198)
        - Draft, undated (Box 25, Folder 199)
        - Drafts, 1950, undated (Box 26, Folder 200-205)
        - List of corrections, undated (Box 26, Folder 206)
        - Galley proof, 1950 September
        - Page proofs, 1950
      - Unidentified
        - Unidentified manuscript, undated (Box 27, Folder 207-210)
    - Plays
      - "Angela is Twenty-Two"
        - Playscripts, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 211-216)
        - Playscripts, 1938 (Box 29, Folder 217-223)
        - Playscripts, 1938-1939 (Box 30, Folder 224-231)
        - Playscripts, 1938-1939 (Box 31, Folder 232-235)
        - Playscripts for part of Dr. Hilary Jerrett, undated (Box 31, Folder 236-240)
        - "Miscellany of intermediate pages...", 1939 (Box 31, Folder 241)
        - Blueprints for stage designs, 1938 November 29
        - Production notes and materials, undated (Box 32, Folder 242-244)
        - Press release, undated (Box 32, Folder 245)
        - Printed ephemera, undated (Box 32, Folder 246)
      - "Felicia Speaking"
        - Notes and prologue, undated (Box 32, Folder 247)
        - Playscripts, 1940 (Box 32, Folder 248-251)
      - "Jayhawker"
        - Pages from playscript, undated (Box 32, Folder 252)
      - "President Pip"
        - Playscript for Act Three, undated (Box 32, Folder 253)
      - "Publish Glad Tidings"
        - Playscripts, 1937, undated (Box 33, Folder 254-255)
      - "Queeny and the Jopes"
        - Playscripts, 1938 (Box 33, Folder 256-259)
      - "Responsible"
        - Notes, undated (Box 33, Folder 260)
        - Playscripts, undated (Box 34, Folder 261-269)
    - Shorter Works
      - "Adam and Eve Treatment", undated (Box 35, Folder 270)
      - "All Wives Are Angels," short story, undated (Box 35, Folder 271)
      - "America Unabashed," review, undated (Box 35, Folder 272)
      - [American Association for the Promotion of Teaching to the Deaf], form letter, 1910 June 25 (Box 35, Folder 273)
      - "Beautiful Bill of Beniciay", 1910 (Box 35, Folder 274)
      - "Black Blood", undated (Box 35, Folder 275)
      - "Bongo," short story, [1930?] (Box 35, Folder 276)
      - "The Boxers of M. Voltaire," review, undated (Box 35, Folder 277)
      - "Breaking Into Print," essay, undated (Box 35, Folder 278)
      - "A Canticle of Great Lovers," poem, undated (Box 35, Folder 279)
      - "Carry Your Own Suitcase," short story, undated (Box 35, Folder 280)
      - "The Cat of the Stars", 1919 September 4 (Box 35, Folder 281)
      - "Catalog of Dreams," poem, 1950 July (Box 35, Folder 282)
      - "Christmas 1909," poems (Box 35, Folder 283)
      - "Citizen of the Mirage," short story, undated (Box 35, Folder 284)
      - "City of Mercy", undated (Box 35, Folder 285)
      - "Dear Editor," short story, undated (Box 35, Folder 286)
      - "The Death of Arrowsmith," obituary, undated (Box 35, Folder 287)
      - "The Desire of the Prairie", undated (Box 35, Folder 288)
      - "Dollar Chasers," short story, undated (Box 36, Folder 289-291)
      - "The Enchanted Hour," short story, undated (Box 36, Folder 292-293)
      - "Enemies of the Book," speech, 1936 May 11 (Box 36, Folder 294)
      - "Essay on Style," essay, undated (Box 36, Folder 295)
      - "Fellow Trooper," short story, undated (Box 36, Folder 296)
      - "Fools, Liars, Mr. Devoto," review, drafts and galley proof, 1944 April 18 (Box 36, Folder 297)
      - "Free Us From Freedom," poem, undated (Box 36, Folder 298)
      - "Gentlemen, This Is the Revolution," review, undated (Box 36, Folder 299)
      - "The Ghost Patrol," short story, 1917 (Box 36, Folder 300)
      - "The Glory Trail," poem, [1950?] (Box 36, Folder 301)
      - "Go East, Young Man," short story, 1930 December (Box 36, Folder 302)
      - "The Golden Half-Century," essay, 1935 (Box 36, Folder 303)
      - "The Good Sport," short story, 1920 December 11 (Box 36, Folder 304)
      - "The Great Director", undated (Box 36, Folder 305)
      - "The Hack Driver", 1923 August 29 (Box 36, Folder 306)
      - "The Happy Man," poem, 1950 June (Box 36, Folder 307)
      - "Harold Stassen, a Man", undated (Box 36, Folder 308)
      - "Harri," short story, undated (Box 37, Folder 309-310)
      - "He Gave Till It Hurt," short story, undated (Box 37, Folder 311)
      - "He Loved His Country," short story, undated (Box 37, Folder 312)
      - "Hermit on a Florence Hill," poem, 1950 May (Box 37, Folder 313)
      - "The Hippocratic Oath," short story, undated (Box 37, Folder 314)
      - "Hobohemia," drafts and play adaptation, undated (Box 37, Folder 315-319)
      - "I'm an Old Newspaper Man Myself", undated (Box 37, Folder 320)
      - Introduction to In New England Fields and Woods by Rowland E. Robinson, undated (Box 38, Folder 321)
      - [Introduction to] Litte Orvie by Booth Tarkington, undated (Box 38, Folder 322)
      - [Introduction to The Diary of Our Own Samuel Pepys by Franklin Adams], undated (Box 38, Folder 323)
      - [Introduction to The Way of a Transgressor by Negley Farson], undated (Box 38, Folder 324)
      - "Is This a Dagger, So What?" short story, 1927 November 27 (Box 38, Folder 325)
      - "Joy-Joy," short story, [1917?] (Box 38, Folder 326)
      - "Keep Out of the Kitchen," short story, 1929 October (Box 38, Folder 327)
      - "The Kidnapped Memorial," short story, 1919 June (Box 38, Folder 328)
      - "Land," short story, 1931 September 12 (Box 38, Folder 329-330)
      - "A Letter From the Queen," short story, 1929 February (Box 38, Folder 331)
      - "Life and the Young Women," essay, 1945 September 11 (Box 38, Folder 332)
      - "Main Streets and Babbitts of Britain", 1928 July 14 (Box 38, Folder 333)
      - "Main Street Goes to War," script, [circa 1942] (Box 38, Folder 334)
      - "A Matter of Business," short story, undated (Box 38, Folder 335)
      - "Metropolitan Opera Broadcast", 1944 December 16 (Box 38, Folder 336)
      - "Midnight Alley," short story, undated (Box 38, Folder 337-339)
      - "Moths in the Arc Light," short story, undated (Box 38, Folder 340)
      - "My First Day in New York," essay, undated (Box 38, Folder 341)
      - "Nature, Inc.," short story, 1915 October 2 (Box 38, Folder 342)
      - "Nelson's Encyclopedia", 1946 August 21 (Box 39, Folder 343)
      - "Noble Experiment," short story, 1930 August (Box 39, Folder 344)
      - "Nobody to Write About," short story, undated (Box 39, Folder 345)
      - "Obscenity and Obscurity", 1945 July (Box 39, Folder 346)
      - "Ode to His Catalepsy: David C. Powers", undated (Box 39, Folder 347)
      - "The Other Side of the House", 1915 November 27 (Box 39, Folder 348)
      - [Poems], 1905-1950 (Box 39, Folder 349-352)
      - "The Post-Mortem Murder", 1921 May (Box 39, Folder 353)
      - "Preface to "Those Were the Days"" by David Cohn, undated (Box 39, Folder 354)
      - "Proper Gander," short story, undated (Box 39, Folder 355)
      - "Prophets in a Wood," poem, 1950 March (Box 39, Folder 356)
      - "Radio Speech", 1944 August 21 (Box 39, Folder 357)
      - "Radio Talk", 1944 October 28 (Box 39, Folder 358)
      - "Rambling Thoughts on Literature as a Business," essay, undated (Box 39, Folder 359)
      - "A Reasonable Place to Live In," essay, undated (Box 39, Folder 360)
      - "Reparationsfibel," essay, undated (Box 39, Folder 361)
      - [Review of] Swedish Immigrants in Lincoln's Time by Nels Hokanson, undated (Box 39, Folder 362)
      - "Ring Around a Rosy," short story, 1931 June 6 (Box 39, Folder 363)
      - "The Sac of Fortune", undated (Box 39, Folder 364)
      - "The Scarlet Sign", 1917 June (Box 39, Folder 365)
      - "A Self-Portrait", undated (Box 39, Folder 366)
      - "Self Portrait", undated (Box 39, Folder 367)
      - "Self Portrait", 1927 August (Box 39, Folder 368)
      - "Shadow and Substance", 1939 December 22 (Box 39, Folder 369)
      - "The Shadowy Glass," short story, 1918 June 22 (Box 39, Folder 370)
      - [Short story notes], undated (Box 39, Folder 371)
      - "The Shrinking Violet," short story, 1919 February 15 (Box 39, Folder 372)
      - "Speed," short story, 1925 December (Box 39, Folder 373)
      - "Storm in the West," notes and drafts of screenplay, 1943 (Box 40, Folder 374-377)
      - "A Story With a Happy Ending," short story, 1917 March 17 (Box 40, Folder 378)
      - "The Sun is on Hollywood," essay, undated (Box 40, Folder 379)
      - "The Swept Hearth," short story, 1918 September 21 (Box 40, Folder 380)
      - "Tag Line," short story, undated (Box 40, Folder 381)
      - "The Tamarack Lover," short story, 1918 February (Box 40, Folder 382)
      - "There was a Prince," short story, 1929 June (Box 40, Folder 383)
      - "They Had Magic Then," short story, undated (Box 40, Folder 384)
      - "Things," short story, 1919 February 22 (Box 40, Folder 385)
      - "To All Men," poem, 1950 June (Box 40, Folder 386)
      - "To Betty," poems, 1949 (Box 40, Folder 387)
      - "To the Pulitzer Prize Committee", 1926 May 6 (Box 40, Folder 388)
      - "Twenty-Four Hours in June", 1917 February 17 (Box 41, Folder 389)
      - "Undergraduate themes", undated (Box 41, Folder 390)
      - "Undiscovered Country" or "For Us the Living", undated (Box 41, Folder 391)
      - "Verse of Sinclair Lewis", undated (Box 41, Folder 392)
      - "The Watcher Across the Road," short story, 1919 May 24 (Box 41, Folder 393)
      - Waterloo, Iowa "Courier" notes, 1908 (Box 41, Folder 394)
      - "Way I See It," short story, 1920 May 29 (Box 41, Folder 395)
      - "What a Man!" short story, 1929 August (Box 41, Folder 396)
      - "What the Young Soldier Should Write," essay, undated (Box 41, Folder 397)
      - "When I was a Page in the Gothic Age..." poem, undated (Box 41, Folder 398)
      - "When the Socialists are Soaking...", undated (Box 41, Folder 399)
      - "The Whisperer," short story, 1917 August 11 (Box 41, Folder 400)
      - "The Whittler," poem, 1950 June (Box 41, Folder 401)
      - "Why I Love the Italians," essay, undated (Box 41, Folder 402)
      - "The Willow Walk," short story, 1918 August 10 (Box 41, Folder 403-404)
      - "Wolfes and Wolves," review, 1945 June 3 (Box 41, Folder 405)
      - "A Woman by Candlelight," short story, 1917 July 28 (Box 42, Folder 406)